<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<RSS version="2.0"><channel><title>اخبار جهان</title><item><title>Russian Drone Hits Romanian Apartment Building, Officials Say - The New York...</title><description>Russian Drone Hits Romanian Apartment Building, Officials Say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesNATO members condemn Russia after drone slams into Romania apartment building, wounding two&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNRussian drone hits residential building in Nato member Romania&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianDrone hits Romania apartment block during Russian attack on neighboring Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsEU says Russia has crossed 'another line' after drone hits Romanian apartment block&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBC</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 11:41:12</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e94ab748444c</link></item><item><title>Soldier killed in Hezbollah drone attack as Israel widens strikes on terror...</title><description>Soldier killed in Hezbollah drone attack as Israel widens strikes on terror group&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelLearning from Ukraine, Hezbollah is now using fibre-optic drones to hit Israel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCIDF Sergeant Rotem Yanai, 20, was killed after she fell during an operational activity in northern Israel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;i24NEWSIsraeli army turns to US after Hezbollah drones strike military sites: Report&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Anadolu AjansıSgt. Rotem Yanai killed during operational activity in northern Israel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 09:39:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#903c93728739</link></item><item><title>Canadian warship transits Taiwan Strait despite China’s warning - The Globe and...</title><description>Canadian warship transits Taiwan Strait despite China’s warning&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Globe and MailSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:29:54</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#30ab8c21c7d4</link></item><item><title>US says Iran launched ‘egregious ceasefire violation,’ testing fragile truce - Politico</title><description>US says Iran launched ‘egregious ceasefire violation,’ testing fragile truce&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PoliticoIran reportedly launches missiles as Trump mulls deal to pause war for two months&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBCStatement from CENTCOM on Recent Iranian Aggression &gt; U.S. Central Command &gt; Press Release View&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;centcom.milU.S. military accuses Iran of ceasefire violation after Kuwait comes under missile attack&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PBSCentral Command: Iran attack on Kuwait an ‘egregious ceasefire violation’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Hill</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 01:09:14</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#080409f2e21a</link></item><item><title>Iran, Gas Prices, the Ballroom: Trump Professes Indifference Over Fallout - The...</title><description>Iran, Gas Prices, the Ballroom: Trump Professes Indifference Over Fallout&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesNo Way to Make a Deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The AtlanticTrump says he can outwait Iran, dismisses midterm election pressure&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersDonald Trump says US 'not satisfied' with Iran deal yet&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCTrump: ‘I don’t care about the midterms’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Politico</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 00:46:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#5713da550745</link></item><item><title>'Complete fabrication': White House rejects Iranian report on Hormuz reopening, US troop...</title><description>'Complete fabrication': White House rejects Iranian report on Hormuz reopening, US troop pullback in draft peace deal | World News&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Hindustan TimesMay 28, 2026 — US and Iran reach tentative agreement though Trump hasn’t signed off on it&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNUS, Iran Reach Deal on Extended Ceasefire Pending Trump Approval&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comVance says U.S. and Iran are "very close" to a deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AxiosA Draft U.S.-Iran Plan Is Said to Be on the Table. Here’s What to Know.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 18:54:14</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#8f116271d67b</link></item><item><title>Netanyahu orders Israeli army to seize ‘70% of Gaza Strip’, violating ceasefire...</title><description>Netanyahu orders Israeli army to seize ‘70% of Gaza Strip’, violating ceasefire deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianNetanyahu Says Israel Will Expand Control Over Gaza Strip to 70%&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comNetanyahu says he has directed IDF to increase control of Gaza to 70%&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCNetanyahu says he directed Israeli military to take over 70% of Gaza&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNNetanyahu tells IDF to seize 70% of Gaza Strip in threat to fragile ceasefire&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Independent</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 21:44:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#9b9bf2a51363</link></item><item><title>How Israel has emptied southern Lebanon far beyond the front lines -...</title><description>How Israel has emptied southern Lebanon far beyond the front lines&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersIsrael intensifies strikes on Lebanon during ceasefire, videos show&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCIsrael Strikes Beirut, Expanding Offensive in Lebanon&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesIsraeli military strikes southern suburb of Beirut before crucial Lebanon-Israel talks in Washington&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsNo End in Sight: Israel Expands War on Lebanon, Orders Evacuation of 14% of Country&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Democracy Now!</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 17:34:26</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#115cc38b5a2f</link></item><item><title>Japan woos Philippine leader during state visit with arms sales and China...</title><description>Japan woos Philippine leader during state visit with arms sales and China in mind&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsJapan, Philippines to discuss information sharing pact to ease arms exports&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersJapan and Philippines agree to elevate ties to new level amid China concerns&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Japan TimesTakaichi to Meet Philippines’ Marcos to Deepen Security Ties&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comJapan-Philippines ties strengthen, thanks to China&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Semafor</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 05:22:34</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7c8876256425</link></item><item><title>Israel, Russia included in UN sexual violence blacklist - dw.com</title><description>Israel, Russia included in UN sexual violence blacklist&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comIsrael to Cut Ties With U.N. Chief Over Its Inclusion on Sexual Violence Blacklist&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesUN ‘adds Israel to blacklist’ for conflict-related sexual violence&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraIsraeli and Russian forces added to UN blacklist for sexual violence in conflict zones&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsIsrael accuses UN of placing it on same sexual violence blacklist as Hamas terrorists, severs ties&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Fox News</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 06:15:34</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#d0559bac3a3f</link></item><item><title>Exclusive-US carries out new strikes in Iran against military site, official says...</title><description>Exclusive-US carries out new strikes in Iran against military site, official says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;YahooIran and U.S. trade new strikes as Trump dismisses pressure to end war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsUS launches defensive strikes against Iran, intercepts multiple threatening drones: officials&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Fox NewsMay 27, 2026 - Trump says he won’t rush Iran deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNUS and Iran trade attacks as sources report tentative agreement to extend ceasefire - as it happened&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 03:21:26</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b226ee234f07</link></item><item><title>Spain distances itself from call for EU to get tougher on China...</title><description>Spain distances itself from call for EU to get tougher on China&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euEurope Is Edging Closer to a Trade War With China. Here’s Why.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesEU to discuss potential restrictions on Chinese imports amid fears of overreliance&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianWhy Europe must embrace tariffs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesEuropean leaders get ready to ‘act now’ amid rising fears of ‘China shock 2.0’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;South China Morning Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:59:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#00d0527a1ab2</link></item><item><title>5 of 7 people trapped in flooded Laos cave for more than...</title><description>5 of 7 people trapped in flooded Laos cave for more than a week found alive, rescuers say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS News‘Essentially diving in coffee’: Australian diver among team rushing to rescue people trapped in flooded Laos cave&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianDiver who helped save soccer team in Thailand holds out hope miners trapped in Laos cave are still alive&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsRescuers work to drain flooded Laos cave to free 5 villagers and search for 2 still missing&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The HillFive People Stuck in Flooded Laos Cave Are Found Alive&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 14:24:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#09909d310ecf</link></item><item><title>US, Mexico, Canada announce Ebola-related travel measures ahead of World Cup -...</title><description>US, Mexico, Canada announce Ebola-related travel measures ahead of World Cup&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersTrilateral statement from the United States, Mexico and Canada on public health travel measures&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;canada.caCanada will require self-isolation for people traveling from Congo, Sudan and Uganda due to Ebola&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsCanada clamping down on travel, immigration from central Africa amid Ebola outbreak&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBCOpinion: Suspending immigration over Ebola is misguided and goes against international law&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Globe and Mail</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:50:09</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#08c56a099d3a</link></item><item><title>France Finally Repeals Its 17th-Century Slavery Law - Newser</title><description>France Finally Repeals Its 17th-Century Slavery Law&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NewserFrance’s parliament votes to repeal slavery-era Black Code, with tears and history in the chamber&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsOpinion | The Brutal History That France Prefers to Ignore Is Being Heard at Last&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesMacron says France must address issue of reparations for its role in slave trade&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianFrance moves to symbolically repeal slavery legislation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 16:14:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#6806ac8973a0</link></item><item><title>Russian Offensive Campaign Assessment, May 28, 2026 - Institute for the Study...</title><description>Russian Offensive Campaign Assessment, May 28, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Institute for the Study of WarThe Russia-Ukraine War Report Card, May 20, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Russia MattersWednesday, May 27. Russia’s War On Ukraine: News And Information From Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ForbesA Big Week for Ukraine’s Forgotten War With Russia | U.S. News Decision Points | U.S. News&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;U.S. News &amp; World ReportWar in Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 07:04:19</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#fd369df3e08b</link></item><item><title>El Niño clashes with climate change as UN warns record heat is...</title><description>El Niño clashes with climate change as UN warns record heat is coming&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comThink it’s hot now? The next five years will smash records, UN says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsWorld almost certain to endure record hot year by 2030, UN warns&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianGlobal temperatures set to stay near record levels: UN weather agency&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;UN NewsGlobal temperatures to reach near-record highs in next five years, report finds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 12:35:52</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#726c71d4b28c</link></item><item><title>Europe urged to ‘kick the fossil fuel addiction’ amid record May heat...</title><description>Europe urged to ‘kick the fossil fuel addiction’ amid record May heat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comWhy Europe is the fastest-warming continent&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comParis Heat Wave Set to Peak Before Weekend Relief&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.com‘Mind-bogglingly crazy’: Europe’s deadly, early heatwave is smashing records&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;YahooA deadly heat wave hits Europe, with decades-old temperature records falling&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Washington Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 10:30:48</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#0d023a066014</link></item><item><title>Ukraine: Russia has failed - Brussels Signal</title><description>Ukraine: Russia has failed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Brussels Signal‘There is profound disappointment in him’: mood in Russia turns against Putin&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianPutin’s moment of truth: End the war or embrace Stalinism&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Telegraph'Self-destructive' Putin loses home support as Ukraine war rages on - Press Review&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24Putin Can No Longer Hide His Catastrophe&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Atlantic</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 10:27:42</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#90530355bd27</link></item><item><title>Extremist Israeli settlers: EU lists four entities and three individuals - consilium.europa.eu</title><description>Extremist Israeli settlers: EU lists four entities and three individuals&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;consilium.europa.euEU sanctions ‘extremist’ Israeli settlers in occupied West Bank&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraEU sanctions Israeli settlers, expands sanctions to Hamas' Politburo members&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersGreater Israel: the origins of the settler movement now threatening to annexe the West Bank&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The ConversationEU Council formally names 3 individuals, 4 entities it is sanctioning over settler violence&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of Israel</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 17:34:01</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2829a0ecc9e2</link></item><item><title>Magyar’s EU reset heads for Brussels reality check - politico.eu</title><description>Magyar’s EU reset heads for Brussels reality check&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euMagyar pushes for breakthrough to secure frozen EU funds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesHungary is on a 'very clear and steadfast' path to restore rule of law, EU justice commissioner says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comAid for trade&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EuractivHUNGARY PM MAGYAR SAYS HE WOULD SOON SUBMIT HUNGARY'S OFFICIAL REQUEST TO JOIN EUROPEAN PUBLIC PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;news.cgtn.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 23:39:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#8624573b265a</link></item><item><title>Colombia election outcome could reshape copper investment - Mining.com</title><description>Colombia election outcome could reshape copper investment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mining.comA ‘Promising Democracy’ That Can’t Stop Fighting Itself&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The AtlanticColombia’s pivotal, polarised election could not be tighter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistCould a Marxist Take Over Conservative Colombia? The Polls Say Yes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJColombians will vote Sunday in a high-stakes test of President Gustavo Petro’s agenda&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP News</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 15:45:35</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#aa5c683777fc</link></item><item><title>Russia will not choose who speaks for Europe in potential Ukraine talks,...</title><description>Russia will not choose who speaks for Europe in potential Ukraine talks, EU ministers say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersRussia on the back foot with dynamics of war shifting in Ukraine’s favour, EU says – as it happened&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianBefore Europe Anoints Someone to Talk to Putin, It Debates What to Talk About&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesCan the EU find a Russia whisperer to mediate an end to the war in Ukraine?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCEU will never be a neutral mediator between Ukraine and Russia: Kallas&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:31:08</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b9e6e705094b</link></item><item><title>Ukraine Opened Russia’s Notorious Oreshnik Missile. Here’s What’s Inside - UNITED24 Media</title><description>Ukraine Opened Russia’s Notorious Oreshnik Missile. Here’s What’s Inside&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;UNITED24 MediaRussian Offensive Campaign Assessment, May 25, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Institute for the Study of WarRussia hits Ukraine with Oreshnik missile in one of war's biggest attacks on Kyiv&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersRussia pressures U.S., Ukraine’s allies to flee Kyiv, threatening ‘systematic strikes’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsIs a shift "in favor of Ukrainian forces" behind a Russian warning to foreigners in Kyiv?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS News</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 16:33:42</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#6464ac8a1d2e</link></item><item><title>Australian woman charged over travel to Syria to join Islamic State -...</title><description>Australian woman charged over travel to Syria to join Islamic State&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NPRAustralian woman held in custody on charges of traveling to Syria to join Islamic State group&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsAustralia charges woman who returned from Syria with joining Islamic State&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCAfter escaping sexual slavery, Yazidis re-traumatised by return of 'ISIS brides'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Australian Broadcasting CorporationPlanes carrying 19 Australians linked to the Islamic State group land in Melbourne and Sydney&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yahoo</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 20:03:04</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e611fb488a70</link></item><item><title>At least 16 students killed in fire at Kenya girls school dorm...</title><description>At least 16 students killed in fire at Kenya girls school dorm&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al Jazeera16 students killed as fire tears through Kenya school dormitory&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNUtumishi Girls Academy fire: Questions over safety as 16 pupils die in another Kenya blaze&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBC16 Students Killed, 74 Injured After School Dormitory Catches Fire While They're Sleeping&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;People.comUtumishi Girls fire: Survivors reveal suspected arson, say dorm was locked from inside&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Daily Nation</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 13:26:58</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#3af4227d1d0b</link></item><item><title>Ukraine to buy 20 new Gripen jets, Sweden to donate older jets...</title><description>Ukraine to buy 20 new Gripen jets, Sweden to donate older jets sooner&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Defense NewsUkraine war briefing: Gripen fighter jet deal ramps up after Zelenskyy visit to Sweden&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianUkraine to receive long-range Meteor missiles alongside first batch of Gripen fighters&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаUkraine and Sweden take steps towards Ukrainian Gripen acquisition&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SaabUkraine to acquire up to 20 Gripen fighter jets, on track to receive batch of older models&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Breaking Defense</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 17:51:57</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#54fdf28d6ac5</link></item><item><title>Uganda Closes Border With Congo as Ebola Fears Rise - The New...</title><description>Uganda Closes Border With Congo as Ebola Fears Rise&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesUganda shuts DR Congo border as Ebola outbreak continues to grow&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CIDRAPUganda closes its border with Congo, where suspected cases of rare Ebola type are surging&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PBSEbola: Uganda closes border with DR Congo as virus spreads&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comEbola’s threat in Uganda extends far beyond public health&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Hill</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 18:38:24</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#3d3a8b7b567c</link></item><item><title>On the ground with Ukraine's drone forces targeting Russia's battlefield rear -...</title><description>On the ground with Ukraine's drone forces targeting Russia's battlefield rear&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersUkraine is turning the tables&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesUkraine’s foreign minister says drone attacks in Russia could pressure Putin to end war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PBSWestern arms makers are lining up to test their weapons on Ukraine's battlefields&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Business InsiderHow New Interceptors Are Transforming Drone Warfare in Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Dispatch</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 00:53:23</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#ad511f6501bf</link></item><item><title>Millionaire populist ‘El Tigre’ vows to make Colombia great again - The...</title><description>Millionaire populist ‘El Tigre’ vows to make Colombia great again&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The TelegraphColombia presidential candidate De La Espriella proposes mega-prisons, crime crackdown&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersColombia far-right surge spells danger for Palestine solidarity&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New ArabFlorida Rep. Salazar Backs Conservative Candidate in…&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;inklThe far right takes flight in Colombia under Abelardo de la Espriella&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EL PAÍS English</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 13:01:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#709983c0c853</link></item><item><title>US-China conflict over Taiwan risks a nuclear escalation, study finds - Reuters</title><description>US-China conflict over Taiwan risks a nuclear escalation, study finds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersHow partisan is Taiwan’s security debate?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BrookingsAfter Xi’s Warning on Taiwan, He and Trump Strike Positive Tone&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesChina vs Taiwan: The Geography of an Unfinished War&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem Strategic TribuneReading Taiwan's Mind - 想想Thinking Taiwan - 想想台灣，想想未來&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;thinkingtaiwan.net</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 04:32:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e5245c699c1a</link></item><item><title>Italian Police Uncover Dead Mob Boss’s $230 Million Business Empire - The...</title><description>Italian Police Uncover Dead Mob Boss’s $230 Million Business Empire&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesVillas, cars and cash: Italy seizes dead Mafia mobster's millions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCItaly seizes gold, luxury villas and cash tied to Sicilian Mafia drug-trafficking gains&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ABC News - Breaking News, Latest News and VideosItaly seizes $232m in Mafia assets tied to Cosa Nostra&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al Jazeera"Vast fortune" belonging to legendary Mafia boss seized by police in Italy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS News</description><pubDate>2026-05-29 03:43:02</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#249a4b02d3d6</link></item><item><title>Iran’s forever war: Deal or no deal, Iran’s challenge to America will...</title><description>Iran’s forever war: Deal or no deal, Iran’s challenge to America will outlast Trump&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNBombs, Bargains and Bluster: Trump’s Iran Approach Sows Confusion&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesTrump still thinks he’s winning in Iran&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;vox.comTrump’s Iran Bind Deepens With Hormuz Shut and Hawks Pushing War&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comTrump's room to maneuver narrows as US, Iran close in on framework deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 07:30:07</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#780430f09ccb</link></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of military chief Mohammed Odeh; defiant funeral held in...</title><description>Hamas confirms death of military chief Mohammed Odeh; defiant funeral held in Gaza City&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelPalestinians mourn 10 killed in Eid strikes as Netanyahu vows wider control of the strip&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsHamas confirms that Israeli strikes killed its new military leader in Gaza City&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PBSTargeted killings haven’t improved Israel’s strategic regional position — experts&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelPalestinians mourn slain Hamas militant chief as Israel escalates Gaza attacks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 19:43:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4fbe8568a956</link></item><item><title>Iran war drives multi-year missile defense gap - Axios</title><description>Iran war drives multi-year missile defense gap&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AxiosRebuilding U.S. Missile Inventory: A Multiyear Project&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CSIS | Center for Strategic and International StudiesRebuilding US weapons stockpile may ‘take years’ post-Iran war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraUS munitions depleted by Iran war will take years to restore, analysis finds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Military TimesUS will need years to replenish stockpiles of advanced weapons used in Iran war, new analysis finds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP News</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 13:10:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#10fb80ff7d71</link></item><item><title>EU’s big six reach deal on key markets package - politico.eu</title><description>EU’s big six reach deal on key markets package&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euGermany shifts on EU oversight of financial services&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesGermany open to compromise on EU capital markets union, finance minister says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersSome of ESMA’s empowerments need further framing, legal service says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;MLexTop EU Economies Vow To Speed Up Financial Integration&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Barron's</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 22:37:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#53e9780d556d</link></item><item><title>Norway becomes ninth country to come under French nuclear deterrence scheme -...</title><description>Norway becomes ninth country to come under French nuclear deterrence scheme&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24Norway will come under France's nuclear umbrella, leaders say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersMacron Says Norway Agrees to Work Closely on Nuclear Deterrence&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comFrance Extends Nuclear Umbrella to Norway as Europe Rearms Against Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;UNITED24 MediaNorway joins France’s nuclear deterrence club&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.eu</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 23:42:09</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#f4acfe4f4991</link></item><item><title>Trump Board of Peace's official Gaza reconstruction fund is empty, source says...</title><description>Trump Board of Peace's official Gaza reconstruction fund is empty, source says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comDonald Trump’s Board of Peace fund is empty&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesDonald Trump Board of Peace official fund empty, separate account received donations&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem Post‘The door to the future of Gaza is still closed’: Trump’s reconstruction promises stall&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianTrump’s board of peace is flailing – just like the president&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Independent</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 17:39:44</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#ca2f8dee24bc</link></item><item><title>Swinney rejects call for Holyrood inquiry into Murrell - BBC</title><description>Swinney rejects call for Holyrood inquiry into Murrell&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCWe know what former SNP chief Peter Murrell bought with £400,000 of embezzled funds. What I’d like to know is why&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianSturgeon 'deceived' and 'betrayed' by former husband&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;RTE.ieSturgeon: This week has been the worst of my life&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The TelegraphNicola Sturgeon and the anatomy of a marriage that looks more bizarre every day&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Independent</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 16:06:28</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#d305144ead11</link></item><item><title>Pope urges priests to respect ‘norms of the liturgy’ to avoid confusion...</title><description>Pope urges priests to respect ‘norms of the liturgy’ to avoid confusion at Mass&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EWTN NewsPope Leo calls for 'openness' to church reform that respects tradition&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;National Catholic ReporterPope at Audience: Liturgical tradition and renewal drive evangelization&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vatican NewsThe liturgy sustains the faithful, renewing them in their faith, mission, pope says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Catholic SunFull text: Pope Leo XIV’s general audience given May 27, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Catholic Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 15:47:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1cb0aeeee0d5</link></item><item><title>European Court Rules Against Turkey in Greek Orthodox Clergy Rights Case -...</title><description>European Court Rules Against Turkey in Greek Orthodox Clergy Rights Case&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GreekReporter.comOrthodox priests merit chance to represent their community, despite Istanbul's pushback&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Courthouse NewsTurkey condemned for violating the rights of the Ecumenical Patriarchate&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Orthodox TimesEuropean Court of Human Rights Condemns Turkey, Upholds Rights of the Ecumenical Patriarchate&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Archons of the Ecumenical PatriarchateECHR rules against Turkey in religious freedom case&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;eKathimerini.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 17:21:20</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#f3abb49b84c9</link></item><item><title>Moscow Signs Military Partnership With the Taliban - The Moscow Times</title><description>Moscow Signs Military Partnership With the Taliban&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Moscow TimesRussia signs military partnership with the Taliban&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euIn Sign Of Deepening Ties, Russia And Afghan Taliban Sign Military Deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Radio Free Europe/Radio LibertyMoscow, Taliban forge military alliance in power grab after US Afghanistan exit: reports&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Fox NewsUS, NATO military infrastructure in Afghanistan unacceptable: Shoigu&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Pajhwok Afghan News</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 18:35:13</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#a277972dc141</link></item><item><title>The US will keep embassy in Kyiv open despite Russian threats -...</title><description>The US will keep embassy in Kyiv open despite Russian threats&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euU.S. dismisses claim its diplomats have fled Kyiv as Zelenskyy sends Trump letter asking for air defense&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsUkraine: EU summons Russian envoy after call to leave Kyiv&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comEU states summon Russian envoys over Kyiv threat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraUS says its embassy in Kyiv remains open&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 16:45:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4732a3f316ef</link></item><item><title>Chinese Coal Disaster to Ripple Through Steel, Power, Chemicals - Bloomberg.com</title><description>Chinese Coal Disaster to Ripple Through Steel, Power, Chemicals&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comA coalmine explosion lays bare China’s two-speed economy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistChina’s worst coal mining blast in over a decade kills 82&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNHidden tunnels, fake doors: China probes mining tragedy that killed 82&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersChinese coal mine accident, Cathay Pacific flight turbulence: 5 weekend reads you missed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;South China Morning Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 06:11:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#32cd6b3acc96</link></item><item><title>South Korea detains dissident who fled China in rubber boat - BBC</title><description>South Korea detains dissident who fled China in rubber boat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCDissident escapes China by inflatable boat in fourth attempt to reunite with family&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNDissident detained in South Korea after fleeing China in rubber boat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianA Chinese dissident is in South Korean custody after a perilous escape by rubber boat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsChinese Dissident Spent 30 Hours in Inflatable Dinghy to Escape to South Korea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;National Review</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 14:42:33</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#bd37e0328f53</link></item><item><title>Starmer warns of Russian aggression as UK agrees new treaty with Poland...</title><description>Starmer warns of Russian aggression as UK agrees new treaty with Poland&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCBritain and Poland are set to sign a big new security treaty&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistNew UK-Poland treaty to focus on defence against Russia, Tusk says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersEurope bolsters military alliances over Russia fears&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;SemaforTreaty between the Republic of Poland and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland on a Security and Defence Partnership&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;GOV.UK</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 20:17:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#3b811e2e96a3</link></item><item><title>Bolivia clears path to send troops onto streets to calm protests -...</title><description>Bolivia clears path to send troops onto streets to calm protests&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersBolivian minister rules out president's resignation despite ongoing unrest&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters5 things to know about the protests challenging Bolivia’s new president&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsBolivia’s Crisis Is About More Than Evo Morales&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Americas QuarterlyBolivia into the Abyss&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;North American Congress on Latin America (NACLA)</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 23:16:53</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#77597e65e03f</link></item><item><title>After Two-Week Search, Missing Toronto Teen Found Safe - Anash.org</title><description>After Two-Week Search, Missing Toronto Teen Found Safe&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Anash.orgMissing teen girl found safe in a Toronto home, police say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBCMissing Toronto teenager Esther found safe, police confirm&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Global NewsMissing Toronto Jewish 14-year-old found&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem PostMissing Youth, Bathurst Street and Hotspur Road, UPDATE: Updated Photo and New Website Available&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Toronto Police Service</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 23:45:57</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#54a16c0b48fa</link></item><item><title>How a Tiny Baltic Nation Is Preparing for Possible War With Russia...</title><description>How a Tiny Baltic Nation Is Preparing for Possible War With Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJKristen Michal, the Estonian leader at the sharp edge of Nato&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;MonocleInside Russia’s Propaganda War In NATO’s Easternmost City&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AOL.comSecurity experts dismiss media speculation about Russian attack on Baltic states&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ERR'This Is How Deterrence Works' Against Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Newser</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 06:30:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b6596ed21958</link></item><item><title>The Mideast Is Baffled by Trump’s Call to Expand Abraham Accords -...</title><description>The Mideast Is Baffled by Trump’s Call to Expand Abraham Accords&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesA ruse, a brave gamble or a fantasy? Why Trump’s most puzzling Iran move yet is unlikely to work&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNTrump asked Muslim leaders to sign peace deal with Israel after Iran war ends&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AxiosEven U.S. allies see Trump’s demands on Abraham Accords as odd and easy to ignore&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;MS NOWPress Review - Trump met with 'laughter and silence' by US allies in Gulf region&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 12:51:27</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b05f3de214d7</link></item><item><title>Iran avoids US sanctions via ship-to-ship transfers of oil, may receive payment...</title><description>Iran avoids US sanctions via ship-to-ship transfers of oil, may receive payment for months - report&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem PostThe High-Seas Black Market That Keeps Iran’s Illicit Oil Flowing&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJOpinion: Russian and Iranian ‘shadow fleets’ threaten global maritime order&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CT InsiderOne in every six Strait of Hormuz transits is fraudulently flagged&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Lloyd's ListThe High-Seas Black Market That Keeps Iran's Illicit Oil Flowing -- Commodities Roundup&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;marketscreener.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 12:17:57</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7e63efcb4d8e</link></item><item><title>Nearly 500,000 Russian soldiers have died in Ukraine war, British intelligence agency...</title><description>Nearly 500,000 Russian soldiers have died in Ukraine war, British intelligence agency says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsAlmost 500,000 Russian soldiers killed since start of Ukraine war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCNearly half a million Russians killed in Ukraine war, UK spy chief says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianRussian army loses 960 troops in war against Ukraine over past day&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ukrinform - Ukrainian National News AgencyAlmost half million Russian soldiers killed in Ukraine war, UK spy chief says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Hill</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 22:47:54</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#636775d6be8b</link></item><item><title>3 Russian shadow fleet tankers attacked by drones near Turkey's Black Sea...</title><description>3 Russian shadow fleet tankers attacked by drones near Turkey's Black Sea coast&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentThree tankers reportedly attacked by drones in Black Sea, shipping agency says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersOil Tankers Suffer Drone Attacks Off Turkey’s Black Sea Coast&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comRussians strike Turkish vessel near Odesa Oblast: fire breaks out, crew members injured – photos&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаRussia attacks three foreign merchant vessels in Black Sea overnight – Kuleba&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ukrinform - Ukrainian National News Agency</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:16:58</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#8ee502f85f62</link></item><item><title>Man stabs 3 people at Swiss train station in what authorities call...</title><description>Man stabs 3 people at Swiss train station in what authorities call an ‘act of terror’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsMan arrested after three injured in stabbing at Swiss train station&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCSwitzerland stabbing: Attacker injures three with knife at Swiss train station&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNThree wounded in Swiss train station stabbing labelled ‘act of terror’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraTense Video Shows Switzerland Stabbing Spree Suspect Sprint Past Schoolkids During Attack&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yahoo</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 18:52:20</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#42d645de0e77</link></item><item><title>'You're Humiliating Yourself': Lindsey Graham Ripped After 'Pathetic' New Trump Praise -...</title><description>'You're Humiliating Yourself': Lindsey Graham Ripped After 'Pathetic' New Trump Praise&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;HuffPostLindsey Graham branded ‘pathetic’ for saying Nobel Peace Prize should be renamed Trump Prize&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The IndependentBloodthirsty MAGA Stooge Pushes Unhinged ‘Trump Prize’ Pitch&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Daily BeastNobel Prize should be named after Trump if he expands Abraham Accords: US Senator&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;India TodayUS Senator Lindsey Graham warns Iran deal could fuel militancy in Lebanon and Iraq, escalate Strait of Hormuz risks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Tribune</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 11:53:10</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#ab549915a8fb</link></item><item><title>Traders are skeptical of Iran timeline for Strait of Hormuz reopening -...</title><description>Traders are skeptical of Iran timeline for Strait of Hormuz reopening&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBCHormuz Is a Warning for the Indo-Pacific&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign AffairsEven After a Strait of Hormuz Deal, Moving 1,500 Ships Won’t Be Easy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesWhat happens when the war really ends&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNThe power struggle in the world’s narrow seas&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 20:49:04</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#431b6c8f6881</link></item><item><title>Pressure Grows on Spain’s Leader After Police Search His Party Office -...</title><description>Pressure Grows on Spain’s Leader After Police Search His Party Office&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesSpanish police raid HQ of governing Socialists as corruption probe escalates&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCScandal after scandal lands Spain’s Sánchez on the ropes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euSpain police enter PM Sanchez’s Socialist Party HQ in corruption probe&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraPolice at Spain's ruling Socialists HQ as part of probe into ex party official&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 15:25:09</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#21b22835bbf2</link></item><item><title>Russia’s Land Bridge Becomes a Highway to Hell - Center for European...</title><description>Russia’s Land Bridge Becomes a Highway to Hell&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Center for European Policy Analysis (CEPA)Ukraine hammers Russia’s land corridor to Crimea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euUkrainian AI Drones Are Tearing Into Russian Logistics&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ForbesUkraine launches Logistics Lockdown programme to intensify mid-range attacks on Russian rear – video&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаUkrainians prepare logistics lockdown for Russian army in the south (Ukraine Battlefield update, Day 1,554)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EUobserver</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 00:39:18</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#0ace73e86422</link></item><item><title>Iceland's parliament votes to hold referendum on EU accession talks in August...</title><description>Iceland's parliament votes to hold referendum on EU accession talks in August&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersA Cod Boat, a Coast Guard Flight and a Lot of Debate About the E.U.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesIceland’s foreign minister fears ‘Brexit moment’ in EU accession referendum&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianNation Forced to Act After Trump, 79, Confuses Them for Target&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;YahooWhy Iceland is reconsidering joining the European Union&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Firstpost</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 21:35:44</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e3b578c1d4f6</link></item><item><title>Italy on red alert as France, Portugal beat hottest May day record...</title><description>Italy on red alert as France, Portugal beat hottest May day record&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24Breaking News Highlights Updates: Italy on red alert as France, Portugal beat hottest May day record&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Economic TimesItaly on red alert as France, Portugal beat May record&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;RTE.ieMAPS: How hot will it get in Italy over the Republic Day weekend?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Local ItalyItaly Outshines Portugal, Spain, France, UK, And India With Supreme Red Alert Mandates Amid May 2026 Global Heatwave Crisis: Here’s New Updates&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Travel And Tour World</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 17:39:19</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#9d2b5810ed84</link></item><item><title>Italy is fuming after Ben Gvir’s flotilla stunt. Is Israel losing a...</title><description>Italy is fuming after Ben Gvir’s flotilla stunt. Is Israel losing a top European ally?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelItamar Ben-Gvir has presided over horrific abuse in Israel’s prisons&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistGlobal Sumud Flotilla activists in Hudson Valley recall Gaza aid trip&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WAMCThe theater of punishment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Peoples DispatchMichael Higgins: Mark Carney brags about using terrorist talking points to lecture Israel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;National Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:15:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#6fa5223324d6</link></item><item><title>Arctic Ocean food chain is disrupted as a key tipping point has...</title><description>Arctic Ocean food chain is disrupted as a key tipping point has now been passed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Phys.orgArctic ocean passes 'irreversible' chemical tipping point&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Oceanographic MagazineArctic Ocean passed a tipping point and scientists say it may never recover&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ScienceDailyMelting of Arctic ice has exposed shallow waters to more sunlight and accelerated a process that reduces nitrate, an essential nutrient for sustaining the marine food chain.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CPG Click Petróleo e Gás'Profound implications': Study finds Arctic Ocean ecosystem may have already passed 'major tipping point' in 2009&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BusinessGreen</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 12:30:04</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#10588172f07f</link></item><item><title>Mexican governor says she's "being persecuted" over case of 2 CIA agents...</title><description>Mexican governor says she's "being persecuted" over case of 2 CIA agents killed in drug lab raid&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS News2 U.S. Embassy officials killed in car crash after Mexico drug lab raid&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AOL.comLicensable picture: Maru Campos, Governor Of Chihuahua, Appears Before The Attorney General's Office In CIA Case&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;reutersconnect.comMexico investigates border governor for collaborating with US agencies against cartels&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;voz.usSecurity Assessment / CIA Agents in Mexico&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mexico Business News</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 23:03:05</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#5115d7651e20</link></item><item><title>Passenger disgusted by seatmate’s gross act on packed flight: ‘I hate people’...</title><description>Passenger disgusted by seatmate’s gross act on packed flight: ‘I hate people’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New York PostSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 20:57:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2a3df83c29b2</link></item><item><title>Chef Accused of Mailing Suicide Kits Will Take a Plea - Newser</title><description>Chef Accused of Mailing Suicide Kits Will Take a Plea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NewserKenneth Law: Canadian who allegedly sold poison to Britons won't face justice in UK&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sky NewsFormer chef who supplied poison for suicides to avoid murder charges, angering families&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsCanadian man allegedly linked to over 100 British deaths will not face justice in UK&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The IndependentLittle has changed since Kenneth Law’s arrest, says father whose son died by suicide&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Global News</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 19:30:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4f0f00740582</link></item><item><title>Iran's Precondition: Unfreeze Billions - Newser</title><description>Iran's Precondition: Unfreeze Billions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NewserIran war updates: Tehran’s negotiators in Qatar; Israel pounds Lebanon&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraTo Make a Deal With Trump, Iran Wants Billions of Its Money Unfrozen&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesIran Pursues Deal That Brings Economic Relief Without Handing Trump Victory&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJExclusive: Qatari negotiating team in Tehran to try to help secure US-Iran deal to end war, says source&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reuters</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 01:38:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#a69c939c1bbe</link></item><item><title>Russia Lets Private Firms Buy Heavy Weapons to Defend Sites From Drone...</title><description>Russia Lets Private Firms Buy Heavy Weapons to Defend Sites From Drone Attacks – RBC&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Moscow TimesRussia to task bankers with shooting down Ukrainian drones&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraRussia just passed a law allowing its central bank to down drones&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBCUkraine war briefing: Shoot down drones yourself, Russia tells its banks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianRussian banks to arm themselves against Ukrainian drones&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 20:29:14</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#fb58dd5718a7</link></item><item><title>South Korean Attack Boat Arrives in Canada Ahead of Submarine Program Decision...</title><description>South Korean Attack Boat Arrives in Canada Ahead of Submarine Program Decision&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;USNI NewsKorea’s Hanwha Offers Rockets in Bid for Canada Submarine Deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comHD Hyundai ramps up bid to win Canadian submarine contract&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Korea TimesSponsored Content: The Fleet That Builds a Nation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PoliticoSouth Korea submarine in Canada in sales pitch to supply Canada's fleet&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Spectrum News NY1</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 19:15:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#d60f247fe104</link></item><item><title>Ukraine to Be Fully Integrated Into EU Air Defense, Drone Priorities, Von...</title><description>Ukraine to Be Fully Integrated Into EU Air Defense, Drone Priorities, Von der Leyen Says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv PostEU must change accession system to cater for Ukraine, enlargement chief says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesUkraine Rejects Merz Plan for Halfway-House Deal on Joining EU&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comEU's von der Leyen discussed Ukraine's path to EU membership with Zelenskiy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersBrussels finally has timetable for Ukraine's EU bid&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euractiv</description><pubDate>2026-05-28 03:47:29</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2def29567258</link></item><item><title>Let's stop pretending drones and IT will rebuild Ukraine's economy - The...</title><description>Let's stop pretending drones and IT will rebuild Ukraine's economy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-27 17:46:44</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4a7095f3cb0a</link></item></channel></RSS>