<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<RSS version="2.0"><channel><title>اخبار جهان</title><item><title>U.S. push for Lebanon ceasefire stalls as Israel eyes Beirut strikes - Axios</title><description>U.S. push for Lebanon ceasefire stalls as Israel eyes Beirut strikes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AxiosOil rises as US, Iran trade strikes, Israel moves further into Lebanon&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersCapture of Beaufort Castle in southern Lebanon is both a strategic asset and a historical burden for Israel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Le Monde.frNetanyahu vows to expand Israel’s grip on Lebanon after deepest incursion in 26 years&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsIsrael's Netanyahu orders attacks in Beirut's southern suburbs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Detroit News</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 08:05:02</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#254a5635a142</link></item><item><title>Colombia’s Petro sows doubt about election showing his favored successor heading to runoff against p...</title><description>Colombia’s Petro sows doubt about election showing his favored successor heading to runoff against pro-Trump rival&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsColombian presidency goes to runoff election that could redefine relations with the US&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNDe la Espriella takes spotlight in Colombia's presidential race with promise of crime crackdown&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ABC News - Breaking News, Latest News and VideosRight-Wing Firebrand Surges Into Colombia Runoff, Shaking Political Establishment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJAnti-cartel hardliner channels Trump in bid to end Colombia's leftist era in pivotal election&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Fox News</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 05:32:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1e57ab78f151</link></item><item><title>The bad news keeps coming for Keir Starmer with new trove of Mandelson files due to be published - A...</title><description>The bad news keeps coming for Keir Starmer with new trove of Mandelson files due to be published&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsMandelson files to be published as ministers brace for 'embarrassing' release of messages - live updates&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCU.K. Braces for More Files About Mandelson, Ambassador Tied to Epstein&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesPeter Mandelson ‘contacted new Labour MPs with invitations for dinner’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The TimesNo 10 braced for ‘excruciating’ revelations as messages between Mandelson and ministers to be released – UK politics live&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Guardian</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 15:00:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b97dd0e3af59</link></item><item><title>How Lebanon’s Best Chance to Disarm Hezbollah Failed - The New York Times</title><description>How Lebanon’s Best Chance to Disarm Hezbollah Failed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesIDF says ‘nearly a third’ of Hezbollah’s forces killed during years-long multi-front war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelAs Trump hits the brakes, Hezbollah pushes the limits&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;www.israelhayom.comAnalysis: Lebanon's Shiites face a 'semi-Nakba,' bearing brunt of war&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;upi.comWhat Would It Take to Disarm Hezbollah?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New Yorker</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:51:17</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#052a47355e51</link></item><item><title>‘Rejected job offers in US’: CJP's Abhijeet Dipke on India return, reason for protest | India News -...</title><description>‘Rejected job offers in US’: CJP's Abhijeet Dipke on India return, reason for protest | India News&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Hindustan TimesIndia's viral 'Cockroach' youth group plans street protest in challenge to Modi&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersIndia news: 'Cockroach' party founder plans protests&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.com‘8 lakh signed petition, 1 crore affected’: CJP chief Dipke cites numbers ahead of protest to seek minister resignation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Hindustan Times'Meet me at airport': Cockroach Janta Party founder set to return to Delhi; plans Jantar Mantar protest&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of India</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 13:33:27</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#8fe52d1b90bb</link></item><item><title>Syrian Officers Who Hid in Plain Sight Face War Crime Charges in Austria - The New York Times</title><description>Syrian Officers Who Hid in Plain Sight Face War Crime Charges in Austria&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesAustria launches trial of former Baath regime officials on torture charges&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ANHATwo former Syrian officials accused of torture during al-Assad era go on trial in Austria&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comAustria begins trial of Assad-era officials accused of torture&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New ArabAustria opens trial of two deposed regime officials accused of torture&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;سانا</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 14:31:20</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7bf941c3715c</link></item><item><title>Race against time for Laos cave rescuers as focus shifts to newly discovered shaft - CNN</title><description>Race against time for Laos cave rescuers as focus shifts to newly discovered shaft&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNLaos cave survivors help with plan to find last two missing men&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCHeavy rain threatens search for 2 gold miners still missing in Laos cave after 5 others rescued&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsRescuers search for alternative route to reach 2 missing in a flooded Laos cave&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsLaos cave rescue workers report 'knocking sound' in search for last 2 missing people&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ABC News - Breaking News, Latest News and Videos</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 11:32:51</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#733c2d5733ff</link></item><item><title>Andriy Yermak, Once the Muscle Behind Zelensky, Is Now Crowdfunding Bail Money - The New York Times</title><description>Andriy Yermak, Once the Muscle Behind Zelensky, Is Now Crowdfunding Bail Money&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesUkraine is fighting corruption in Zelensky’s inner circle. That’s worth defending&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The TelegraphCourt acquits key witness in case against anti-corruption detective Mahamedrasulov&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаVolodymyr Zelenskyy and the cancer of Ukrainian corruption&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The WeekZelenskyy's former chief of staff released on €2.7 million bail in anti-corruption probe&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yahoo News Australia</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:32:36</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#bbe24aeb9f6c</link></item><item><title>China responds to Japan-Philippines boundary talks with expanded sea patrols - South China Morning P...</title><description>China responds to Japan-Philippines boundary talks with expanded sea patrols&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;South China Morning PostChina patrols waters east of Taiwan in response to Japan, Philippine maritime border talks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersChina Sends Patrol East of Taiwan After Tokyo-Manila Talks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comPratas Island Is Beijing’s Next Pressure Point and Washington’s Next Test&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;National ReviewCGA warns of increase in Chinese incursions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Taipei Times</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 06:00:51</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7fec5962d5e4</link></item><item><title>Ethiopian election expected to hand leader Abiy's party a landslide win - Reuters</title><description>Ethiopian election expected to hand leader Abiy's party a landslide win&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersEthiopia holds elections with PM Abiy’s party expected to dominate&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraEthiopia’s PM won a Nobel Peace Prize, stoked a civil war - and is set for re-election&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNPolls open in Ethiopia, but not everyone can vote&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCPolls open in Ethiopia’s election that is widely expected to be won by the ruling party&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP News</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 04:31:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#5e9a768aafcb</link></item><item><title>French Navy intercepts sanctioned Russian shadow fleet tanker in Atlantic, Macron says - The Kyiv In...</title><description>French Navy intercepts sanctioned Russian shadow fleet tanker in Atlantic, Macron says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentFrance seizes another sanctioned tanker carrying Russian oil&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNFrance intercepts sanctioned Russian oil tanker, Macron says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCFrench navy, backed by the UK, intercepts Russian oil tanker&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraFrench Navy seizes Russia-linked oil tanker in high seas, Macron says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC News</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 09:54:58</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#5b683c00f7e6</link></item><item><title>Trump’s War Story Blown Up by Jaw-Dropping New Evidence - The Daily Beast</title><description>Trump’s War Story Blown Up by Jaw-Dropping New Evidence&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Daily BeastUS Infrastructure Hit Hard During Iran War, Over 20 Military Sites Damaged Since February 28&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;News18“MVP of Iran War”: U.S. Air Force Boss Calls MQ-9 Reaper Drones the Most Valuable Player Despite 24 Losses&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EurAsian TimesIran Wiped Out 42 U.S. Military Aircraft in Operation Epic Fury — and It’s Just Getting Started&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;National Security Journal20 US military sites damaged in Middle East since start of Iran war: Report&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WION</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 15:31:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#16869880533d</link></item><item><title>Huge blast kills dozens in rebel-held village in Myanmar - BBC</title><description>Huge blast kills dozens in rebel-held village in Myanmar&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBC‘Destroyed beyond recognition’: Dozens dead after explosives detonate in Myanmar town&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsRescuers dig for bodies after a massive mining explosives blast in Myanmar kills at least 38&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NewsdayMore than 45 dead in Myanmar town after massive blast in building storing explosives&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNDozens Killed as Explosion Flattens Rebel-Held Village in Myanmar&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York Times</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 09:53:59</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1faf38b8ffc9</link></item><item><title>Trump Wants Arab States to Recognize Israel. The War Has Made That Harder. - WSJ</title><description>Trump Wants Arab States to Recognize Israel. The War Has Made That Harder.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJA ruse, a brave gamble or a fantasy? Why Trump’s most puzzling Iran move yet is unlikely to work&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNWhy U.S. allies aren’t taking Trump seriously after his push for Arab-Israel normalization&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsThe Mideast Is Baffled by Trump’s Call to Expand Abraham Accords&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesAbraham Accords might lose momentum due to Pakistan, Muslim world&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem Post</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 06:30:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#9eab5283a93b</link></item><item><title>Philippines, Vietnam upgrade ties, say South China Sea peace 'non-negotiable' - Reuters</title><description>Philippines, Vietnam upgrade ties, say South China Sea peace 'non-negotiable'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersVietnam calls off President To Lam’s meeting with Cayetano&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Inquirer.netVietnam, Philippines Elevate Ties as They Navigate China Tension&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comGrab plans autonomous vehicles, delivery robots in Vietnam, pledges long-term investment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;TNGlobalPresident Ferdinand Marcos Jr. and first lady Liza Araneta-Marcos pose for a photo with Vietnamese President Tô Lâm and first lady Ngô Phương Ly at Malacañang in Manila on Monday. (Photos by Noel Pabalate/The Philippine STAR)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;facebook.com</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 06:04:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#908026024753</link></item><item><title>Japan’s defence minister Koizumi rejects China accusations of ‘new militarism’ - Financial Times</title><description>Japan’s defence minister Koizumi rejects China accusations of ‘new militarism’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesJapan's defence minister denies militarism and criticises China's 'huge arsenal'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCJapan Is Stepping Up as Asia’s New Powerbroker&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comJapan’s Point of No Return&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign AffairsJapan’s defense minister rebuffs ‘militarism’ allegation, defends defense policies&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Breaking Defense</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 09:33:38</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4e55eb59a647</link></item><item><title>Hegseth seeks to convince allies U.S. should stay quiet on Taiwan - Fortune</title><description>Hegseth seeks to convince allies U.S. should stay quiet on Taiwan&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;FortuneThe great Indo-Pacific hedge - deeper defence ties as US doubts grow and China ascends&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersAsia reckons with China as Trump pulls back&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PoliticoHegseth’s Message to Asian Partners: Do More to Get More&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesDefense spending, China in Asia and lessons from Ukraine: Takeways from the 2026 IISS Shangri-La Dialogue&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBC</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 19:05:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#667ab591bc27</link></item><item><title>Typhoon Jangmi Approaching Okinawa Prefecture, Amami Islands; Severe Winds, Warning-Level Heavy Rain...</title><description>Typhoon Jangmi Approaching Okinawa Prefecture, Amami Islands; Severe Winds, Warning-Level Heavy Rain Expected ( UPDATE1 )&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Japan News'Intense' Wind and Rain Lash Okinawa as Typhoon Nears&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;YahooWeather Alert – Typhoon – U.S. Consulate General Naha, Okinawa, Japan May 31, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;U.S. Embassy &amp; Consulates in Japan (.gov)Typhoon 06W (Jangmi), # 18: Okinawa in TCCOR 1-E&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Stars and StripesTyphoon expected to bring heavy rain to western, eastern Japan&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Japan Today</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 11:02:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#476cdda1a82b</link></item><item><title>Philippine senator arrested on plunder charge, with no right to bail - AP News</title><description>Philippine senator arrested on plunder charge, with no right to bail&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsWATCH: Tension flares between Cayetano, Remulla during Jinggoy arrest&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Inquirer.netPhilippine Senator Faces Second Arrest Order Over Graft Scandal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comJinggoy Estrada got away with plunder twice. Will there be a 3rd time?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;RapplerA Philippine senator says he will surrender after an anti-graft court ordered his arrest on charge of economic plunder&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;kare11.com</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 14:13:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#9b38a799f009</link></item><item><title>Malaysia enforces ban on social media accounts for children younger than 16 - AP News</title><description>Malaysia enforces ban on social media accounts for children younger than 16&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsMalaysia: Mandatory age verification undermines privacy and free expression&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ARTICLE 19 - Defending freedom of expression and information.Malaysia bars under-16s from social media as new rules come into force&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;South China Morning PostMalaysia Social Media Ban&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bluefield Daily TelegraphMalaysia’s new online safety rules kick in today: What changes for social media users?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Malay Mail</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:33:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#44eda64b7c1f</link></item><item><title>EU Weighs Temporary Freeze on Russia Oil Price Cap Over Iran War - Bloomberg.com</title><description>EU Weighs Temporary Freeze on Russia Oil Price Cap Over Iran War&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comSanctions Stall: EU Weighs Freezing Oil Price Cap to Keep Pressure on Russian Urals&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv PostThe European Union is considering temporarily suspending the adjustment of the price cap mechanism for Russian oil&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BitgetRussia's Dmitriev says Europe needs Russia to survive&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;IntelliNewsEurope’s new oil price caps won’t harm the Russian economy&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;UnHerd</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 13:23:13</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e55ceb2b42f2</link></item><item><title>Nicaraguan Indigenous leader Brooklyn Rivera dies in state custody - Reuters</title><description>Nicaraguan Indigenous leader Brooklyn Rivera dies in state custody&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersProminent Nicaraguan Indigenous Leader Dies in Government Custody&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesIndigenous leader Brooklyn Rivera dies in Nicaragua after nearly 3 years of detention&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NBC NewsNicaragua confirms death in custody of Indigenous leader Brooklyn Rivera&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraNicaragua: Indigenous leader Rivera dies in detention&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 22:26:34</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#24792a47fd45</link></item><item><title>Authorities to introduce 'fuel vouchers,' restrict gasoline sales in occupied Crimea amid shortages...</title><description>Authorities to introduce 'fuel vouchers,' restrict gasoline sales in occupied Crimea amid shortages linked to Ukrainian strikes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentDrivers in Russian-controlled Crimea grapple with gasoline shortages&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersNews from occupied Ukraine: Fuel rationing in Crimea, Storm Shadows 'destroy' Russian targets in Luhansk Oblast&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentPetrol to be distributed by voucher in occupied Crimea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаUkrainian drones disrupt land corridor to occupied Crimea, triggering fuel shortage on peninsula&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Meduza</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 03:41:31</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1b1821abdf01</link></item><item><title>Russia says Ukraine drone struck Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant - dw.com</title><description>Russia says Ukraine drone struck Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 06:35:51</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#4ffacc5a52d7</link></item><item><title>Ukrainian drones hit pipeline, refinery, fuel depot in overnight strikes on Russia - Reuters</title><description>Ukrainian drones hit pipeline, refinery, fuel depot in overnight strikes on Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersUkraine attacks Russian energy sites - what has been hit?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersUkrainian Drones Target Refinery In Latest Attack Deep Inside Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Radio Free Europe/Radio LibertyWiped out Tu-142MR could be a significant blow to the Northern Fleet&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Barents ObserverUkraine drones strike Russian oil facility, as Kyiv and Moscow trade blows&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al Jazeera</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 10:51:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#aee3a9f459c5</link></item><item><title>Tsikhanouskaya's Adviser: Russians, Lukashenko Regime Preparing for Escalation Along Belarus’s Borde...</title><description>Tsikhanouskaya's Adviser: Russians, Lukashenko Regime Preparing for Escalation Along Belarus’s Borders&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv PostConcerns mount that Belarus could be a launchpad for a new Russian offensive in Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsUkraine-Russia war latest: Kremlin says French seizure of tanker ‘bordering on piracy’ as it vows response&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The IndependentLukashenko Responds to Ukrainian General’s List of 500 Targets in Belarus&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv PostRussian Offensive Campaign Assessment, May 26, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Institute for the Study of War</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 12:35:13</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#27a7b19f35b5</link></item><item><title>Ukraine’s military intelligence fields drones able to fly 3,500 km, putting Siberia in range - Eurom...</title><description>Ukraine’s military intelligence fields drones able to fly 3,500 km, putting Siberia in range&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euromaidan PressUkraine turns real-life kills into video game thrills for drone pilots&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Washington PostRobots are redefining the war in Ukraine – and forcing Russia onto the back foot&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNRobot wars: Ukraine now adding ‘land drones’ to its futuristic arsenal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Christian Science MonitorUkraine: How a kamikaze drone partially operated by AI is attacking Russian convoys&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 19:06:53</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1a499e708a2d</link></item><item><title>Hungary Seeks to Oust President in Purge of Orban Allies - Bloomberg.com</title><description>Hungary Seeks to Oust President in Purge of Orban Allies&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comHungary's Magyar threatens legal action if president refuses to resign&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersHungarian PM to remove president and other ‘Orbán puppets’ from office&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesHungary: Tamás Sulyok will not step down as president&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comHungary’s Magyar to amend the constitution to remove President Tamás Sulyok&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP News</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 10:55:59</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#d20e72d8f512</link></item><item><title>Elder Andersen dedicates the Bacolod Philippines Temple - Church News</title><description>Elder Andersen dedicates the Bacolod Philippines Temple&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Church NewsSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 23:42:49</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#50636588306d</link></item><item><title>Malta’s prime minister declares historic victory in snap election - politico.eu</title><description>Malta’s prime minister declares historic victory in snap election&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.euVoting starts in Malta parliamentary elections, ruling party set to win&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersLabour triumphs in Malta election, preliminary results show&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Al JazeeraMaltese cast ballots as Labour government seeks fourth term in snap election&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comIN PHOTOS | Robert Abela's swearing in&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;MaltaToday</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 16:49:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#adcc23162850</link></item><item><title>Scotland’s former leader rejects blame for estranged husband’s embezzlement of party funds - AP News</title><description>Scotland’s former leader rejects blame for estranged husband’s embezzlement of party funds&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsNicola’s only crime was to love too much. And to not notice the Jaguar on the drive | John Crace&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianCall for joint Holyrood-Westminster inquiry into Murrell's embezzlement&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCThe very British banality of the SNP’s shopping scandal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesScottish Nationalists Hang On to Power, Without Authority&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Jacobin</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 14:45:11</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#3e56ad38909a</link></item><item><title>Alberta Wildfires Break Out in Lac la Biche Oil Sands Region - Bloomberg.com</title><description>Alberta Wildfires Break Out in Lac la Biche Oil Sands Region&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comWildfire season returns to Canada's oil sands&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersMultiple lightning wildfires in GPFA over the weekend&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EverythingGPCanada's oil sands on alert as wildfires return&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Quantum Commodity IntelligenceAlberta wildfires threaten oil sands production region&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;World Oil</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 23:12:31</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#fbda4457556c</link></item><item><title>China patrols Scarborough Shoal after Philippines warns of threat - Reuters</title><description>China patrols Scarborough Shoal after Philippines warns of threat&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersManila seeking closer ties with Taipei to deter China&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Taipei TimesThe Philippines is in for a 'long-term struggle' with China over territory, Manila's defense secretary tells CNBC&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBCSouth China Sea: China patrols near Scarborough Shoal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Table.BriefingsPhilippines says Beijing main hurdle to South China Sea code of conduct&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;South China Morning Post</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 09:50:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b518d0b014c3</link></item><item><title>Full transcript of "Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan," May 31, 2026 - CBS News</title><description>Full transcript of "Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan," May 31, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 21:51:17</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#b1882e911da9</link></item><item><title>Ukraine's Zelenskiy seeks progress on peace talks before winter - Reuters</title><description>Ukraine's Zelenskiy seeks progress on peace talks before winter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersZelenskyy says "more pressure" is needed to get Putin to table to negotiate peace deal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsUkraine has limited window for negotiations with Russia, Zelensky says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentZelenskyy: We have a window for talks with Russia before winter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаZelensky: US, Europe could act as joint mediators in talks with Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ukrinform - Ukrainian National News Agency</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 21:31:41</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#134e275241b3</link></item><item><title>Horses bolt through Rome after policeman lights fireworks at parade rehearsal - Reuters</title><description>Horses bolt through Rome after policeman lights fireworks at parade rehearsal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersFireworks reportedly trigger mass horse stampede through Rome streets, injuring several soldiers&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yahoo4 traffic wardens who spurred horse rampage through Rome barred from Republic Day duty (3)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ANSAItalian military horses break free during parade rehearsal in Rome | Italians voted through institutional referendum | Inshorts&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;InshortsHorses bolt during rehearsals for Italy's Republic Day parade, leaving several injured&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ilglobo.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 11:31:43</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#8db2df86a153</link></item><item><title>Russia Risks Fuel Crunch After Record Month of Ukrainian Attacks - Bloomberg.com</title><description>Russia Risks Fuel Crunch After Record Month of Ukrainian Attacks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comRussia bans aviation fuel exports until November 30&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersRussia Bans Jet Fuel Exports Until Late November&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Moscow TimesRussia imposes temporary ban on jet fuel exports&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Anadolu AjansıUkraine’s Drone Strikes Force Fuel Limits Near Moscow&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;UNITED24 Media</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 10:52:50</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#39559a51922f</link></item><item><title>8 Girls Arrested After Dorm Fire Kills 16, Injures Dozens - Newser</title><description>8 Girls Arrested After Dorm Fire Kills 16, Injures Dozens&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Newser8 Girls Arrested in Suspected Arson at School Dorm That Killed 16&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesKenya arrests 8 students suspected of arson in deadly school fire&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNNKenyan police arrest 8 students on suspicion of arson after deadly girls school fire&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ABC News - Breaking News, Latest News and VideosDCI in pursuit of Utumishi Girls fire suspect who went home&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Daily Nation</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 19:20:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#dd08e1840929</link></item><item><title>India’s Hindu Right Has a New Hero: A 17th-Century Warrior King - The New York Times</title><description>India’s Hindu Right Has a New Hero: A 17th-Century Warrior King&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesHindu Right has a new hero, and a cockroach’s guide to identifying an ‘Indian uncle’&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ThePrintThe Sculptor Riding India’s Shivaji Craze&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 12:30:14</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#f08bfcff2a88</link></item><item><title>Short on growth ideas, Putin hosts fifth wartime 'Russian Davos' - Reuters</title><description>Short on growth ideas, Putin hosts fifth wartime 'Russian Davos'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersWhy Putin’s Macro Discipline Is Squeezing Russia’s Main Economic Engine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comRussia overspends on Putin’s war in Ukraine by $28bn&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesRussia’s ballooning $28bn Ukraine war bill forces Putin to make spending cuts&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The IndependentRussia’s War Machine Is Creaking&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Jacobin</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:49:43</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2cabc0356694</link></item><item><title>Ukraine war latest: Russian brigade that committed war crimes in Bucha hit by Ukrainian drone strike...</title><description>Ukraine war latest: Russian brigade that committed war crimes in Bucha hit by Ukrainian drone strike, military says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentRussian Offensive Campaign Assessment, May 31, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Institute for the Study of WarUkraine using AI drones to strike vital convoys supplying Russian troops&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCHighway to Hell: Ukraine's Logistics Lockdown, Taiwan’s Littoral Command and China’s Evolving Nuclear Capability. The Big Five, 31 May edition.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Futura Doctrina | Mick RyanUkraine hammers Russia’s land corridor to Crimea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;politico.eu</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 19:40:19</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2b51f6514904</link></item><item><title>Pashinyan on course for landslide win in Armenia vote, new poll shows - Euronews.com</title><description>Pashinyan on course for landslide win in Armenia vote, new poll shows&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comExclusive: Imported voters, fake websites: Russia's covert efforts to stop Armenia's pivot West&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersFake Pride, masked men and a surge in misinformation ahead of Armenia’s election&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;France 24Reuters: Kremlin planning to bring 100,000 Russia-based Armenians to Armenia to sway elections&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаRussia, the U.S., and the EU Should Keep Out of Armenia’s Domestic Affairs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Oragark</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 09:30:01</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#a38f3b67bc46</link></item><item><title>Ben Gvir said to have forced his way onto ship to film controversial flotilla video - The Times of I...</title><description>Ben Gvir said to have forced his way onto ship to film controversial flotilla video&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelItamar Ben-Gvir has presided over horrific abuse in Israel’s prisons&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistGaza activist says he was 'kicked and punched' by Israeli forces&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCWhy so many Israelis still support Ben-Gvir - and what his actions expose - opinion&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem PostFlotilla activists take evidence of alleged abuse to international court&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Australian Broadcasting Corporation</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 23:47:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7a52dac42baa</link></item><item><title>More than half of shadow fleet oil tankers pose environmental disaster risk - Financial Times</title><description>More than half of shadow fleet oil tankers pose environmental disaster risk&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesSanctioned shadow fleet oil tankers threaten environmental disaster, FT reports&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Kyiv IndependentShadow fleet pollution is burdening under-resourced nations&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Dialogue EarthRussia's shadow fleet is massively corroding and threatens a large-scale environmental disaster - FT&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українські Національні Новини (УНН)‘Ticking time bomb’: Shadow fleet oil tankers risk environmental disaster&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;TVP World</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 07:30:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#52441d8ecb48</link></item><item><title>Zelenskyy alleges Russia is abducting Ukrainian kids and training them to fight - CBS News</title><description>Zelenskyy alleges Russia is abducting Ukrainian kids and training them to fight&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsOPINION: Stolen Children, Identities Erased: Why the World Cannot Look Away&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv Post"Eaglets of Russia": the Ukrainian children being turned into future Russian soldiers&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Українська правдаZelensky claims Ukraine has evidence Russia is forcing country’s stolen children to fight&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The IndependentKremlin-funded propaganda film shows Ukrainian children ‘learning to love’ life in Russia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Meduza</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 20:13:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#f9af3bf399f6</link></item><item><title>Tens of thousands march in support of Turkey’s deposed opposition leader - AP News</title><description>Tens of thousands march in support of Turkey’s deposed opposition leader&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsOusted Turkish opposition leader Ozel draws thousands in Ankara protest&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersTurkey: Ousted CHP leader draws thousands for Ankara rally&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;dw.comTurkey’s Opposition Party Is Mistaking Defeat for Virtue&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;JacobinOpposition fears Erdoğan could trigger snap elections&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euractiv</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 20:35:03</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1943a0578d7c</link></item><item><title>The biggest permanent desert lake threatens with rising waters and hungry crocs - NPR</title><description>The biggest permanent desert lake threatens with rising waters and hungry crocs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NPR</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 15:54:28</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#95cf234d88fe</link></item><item><title>Do Americans really know how much the world hates us? - Salon.com</title><description>Do Americans really know how much the world hates us?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Salon.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 16:30:58</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#3f014bb2d777</link></item><item><title>Gripens: What Impact Will The Swedish Fighter Jet Have In Ukraine? - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty</title><description>Gripens: What Impact Will The Swedish Fighter Jet Have In Ukraine?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Radio Free Europe/Radio LibertyUkraine to buy 20 new Gripen jets, Sweden to donate older jets sooner&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Defense NewsSweden Agrees to Saab Jet Fighter Deal With Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WSJSweden to sell Gripen E/F fighter aircraft to Ukraine&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Government.seUkraine pairs MBDA Meteor missiles with Saab Gripen fighter to counter Russian glide bombs&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yahoo</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 17:57:17</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#98eb5529edce</link></item><item><title>Two teen girls hurt, one seriously, in car-ramming terror attack at West Bank junction - The Times o...</title><description>Two teen girls hurt, one seriously, in car-ramming terror attack at West Bank junction&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelWATCH: IDF raids home of terrorist who carried out Sunday's car ramming attack in Gush Etzion&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem PostArmy raids home of Palestinian terrorist behind Gush Etzion car-ramming&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelTwo Israeli teens wounded in West Bank ramming attack, IDF operating in Hebron&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;HaaretzTeen girls wounded in West Bank ramming attack; terrorist neutralized&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ynetnews</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 01:18:22</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#59a4e5290366</link></item><item><title>Oldest Active Navy Aircraft Carrier To Make Final Overseas Port Call - Forbes</title><description>Oldest Active Navy Aircraft Carrier To Make Final Overseas Port Call&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ForbesUSNI News Fleet and Marine Tracker: May 26, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;USNI NewsUSS Nimitz to Visit Jamaica in Final Stop of Southern Seas 2026 Deployment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;U.S. Embassy in Jamaica (.gov)Nimitz Hosts Caribbean Leaders During Southern Seas 2026 Deployment&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;navy.milU.S. Naval Update Map: May 28, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Stratfor</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 20:15:13</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#904617ac5d57</link></item><item><title>Jewish group to sue over bathhouse ban after ‘Zionist quiz’ for visitors - The Jewish Chronicle</title><description>Jewish group to sue over bathhouse ban after ‘Zionist quiz’ for visitors&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jewish ChronicleMKs advance dissolution of Knesset, with first plenum vote set for later today&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IsraelTwo Jewish women pushed out of Spanish spa, allegedly after staffers see Star of David necklace in disturbing video&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New York Post'Wear the Star of David without fear' say Barcelona Jews after antisemitic sauna incident&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ynetnewsSpanish Jews to sue Barcelona gay spa over alleged exclusion&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;JNS.org</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 16:01:47</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#15875f23dab6</link></item><item><title>China Aims A.I. at Predicting Who Could Pose a Political Risk - The New York Times</title><description>China Aims A.I. at Predicting Who Could Pose a Political Risk&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York TimesChina overhauls world’s biggest surveillance network with advanced AI&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial TimesHow LLMs are changing 'Chinese Firewall' in a country where Facebook, WhatsApp and other social media platforms are banned&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Times of IndiaWhat if a government could predict its critics before they speak? Inside China’s alleged AI-powered...&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Moneycontrol.comChina Exports Surveillance&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The New York Times</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:31:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#0aecec7d11f4</link></item><item><title>Xi’s last frontier: China’s plan to transform its west - Financial Times</title><description>Xi’s last frontier: China’s plan to transform its west&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Financial Times</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 08:01:20</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2c19a00e0a5d</link></item><item><title>Ecuador accused of meddling in Colombian election with tariff vow - BBC</title><description>Ecuador accused of meddling in Colombian election with tariff vow&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCSee more headlines &amp; perspectives on Google News</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 00:10:07</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#86a028c39b21</link></item><item><title>‘To call it a ceasefire is a joke': Israeli soldiers share rare accounts from Gaza with AP - Politic...</title><description>‘To call it a ceasefire is a joke': Israeli soldiers share rare accounts from Gaza with AP&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PoliticoWhat I did in Gaza: an Israeli soldier’s reckoning&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The EconomistUN raises alarm over Israel's killings of Gazans near armistice line&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersAP News in Brief at 6:04 a.m. EDT&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ottumwa Courier'Ceasefire Is a Joke': Israeli Soldiers Recount Ongoing Indiscriminate Killings in Gaza&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Common Dreams</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 02:45:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e64efc5b52a7</link></item><item><title>‘Hellish’ bus 666 returns as FlixBus launches route to Hel - Euronews.com</title><description>‘Hellish’ bus 666 returns as FlixBus launches route to Hel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euronews.comPoland's controversial 'Highway to Hel' 666 bus revived&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCPoland revives controversial ‘Highway to Hel’ 666 bus route&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Independent"The 'Bus to Hell' Rides Again... Poland's Number 666 Bus Makes a Comeback"&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;아시아경제Poland’s 666 bus to Hel returns in new form&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Notes From Poland</description><pubDate>2026-05-30 18:25:20</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#470f95aff785</link></item><item><title>Full transcript: Cindy McCain on "Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan," May 31, 2026 - CBS News</title><description>Full transcript: Cindy McCain on "Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan," May 31, 2026&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CBS NewsCindy McCain to Trump administration: ‘We need help’ with food aid&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Hill'Food security is national security,' McCain warns as WFP faces funding pressure&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PBSUS-Israel war on Iran driving historic levels of global hunger, UN says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The GuardianNumbers Game | Food insecurity and global conflict&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Oxford Student</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 14:02:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#154ab4a79133</link></item><item><title>Man dead after assault in Dublin - BBC</title><description>Man dead after assault in Dublin&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCMan, 21, dies following assault in Dublin city centre&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;RTE.ieMan (21) dies after fatal assault in Dublin city centre&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Irish TimesMan (21) dies after Dublin stabbing as gardaí cordon off large area around Grafton Street&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Irish IndependentMan, 21, stabbed to death amid bank holiday row in Dublin city as Justice Minister Jim O'Callaghan in witness appeal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Irish Sun</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 12:05:17</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#54dc7192000a</link></item><item><title>The 30 Most Walkable Cities In The World—According To A 2026 GuruWalk Report - Forbes</title><description>The 30 Most Walkable Cities In The World—According To A 2026 GuruWalk Report&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ForbesThis City Was Named the Most Walkable Destination in Asia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Travel + LeisureEuropean city named world's most walkable with an 'open-air museum'&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The MirrorTokyo Sparks A Massive Global Travel Boom As Japan’s Revolutionary Walkable Tourism Completely Reinvents How We Explore Asia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Travel And Tour WorldJapan to France and Vietnam to Denmark, The World’s Most Walkable Cities In 2026 Are Reshaping Global Travel Experiences And Redefining Tourism Through Immersive Walkable Urban Exploration&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Travel And Tour World</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 04:30:23</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#7d41fc48c7a8</link></item><item><title>US castigates Europe over defence spend as NATO reassures Asia - Reuters</title><description>US castigates Europe over defence spend as NATO reassures Asia&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersNATO Military Head Says No ‘Drama’ With US, Good on Spending&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bloomberg.comU.S. is right to ask allies to spend more on defense, Dutch deputy PM says&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CNBCNATO allies push back after fresh US warning on defence spending&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Sky News AustraliaWestern Europe's defence spending challenge&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Straits Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 13:01:54</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#243df9fbdc90</link></item><item><title>NYT shareholder calls for probe of Board documents after Kristof article - The Jerusalem Post</title><description>NYT shareholder calls for probe of Board documents after Kristof article&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Jerusalem PostWe all lose when journalism is biased&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The HillBlood Libels and Sexual Violence: Israel, Palestinian Prisoners and The New York Times&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;CounterPunch.orgOpinion: Fall From Grace&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Baltimore Jewish TimesCAMERA Op-Ed: Kristof and the Self-Sabotaging World of Journalism&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;camera.org</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 10:33:16</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#085ef99e2a59</link></item><item><title>Nepal's Time Zone Is a Fiercely Unique One - Newser</title><description>Nepal's Time Zone Is a Fiercely Unique One&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Newser</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 21:39:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#e16254dc2e49</link></item><item><title>Russia’s $30m terror missile keeps missing - Euromaidan Press</title><description>Russia’s $30m terror missile keeps missing&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Euromaidan PressRussian Oreshnik missile fired in January was nine years old, Ukrainian experts say&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ReutersExclusive: Design of the Oreshnik Missile’s Submunitions Revealed&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Мілітарний25% of American components in Russian weapons are counterfeit – Vlasyuk&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;ОборонкаPutin’s ‘unstoppable’ hypersonic missile blows up his own troops in humiliating own goal&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;the-sun.com</description><pubDate>2026-06-01 13:02:43</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1675c91d28e2</link></item><item><title>‘Apologies are never enough’: Prominent religious anti-trafficking advocate on Leo XIV’s Magnifica H...</title><description>‘Apologies are never enough’: Prominent religious anti-trafficking advocate on Leo XIV’s Magnifica Humanitas&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Crux | Taking the Catholic PulseGhana welcomes Pope's apology over Catholic Church's role in slavery&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;BBCPope Leo XIV makes historic apology for Vatican’s role in legitimizing slavery&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;AP NewsKnights of Peter Claver express ‘full support’ for Pope Leo slavery apology&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;OSV NewsIn his first encyclical, Pope Leo apologizes for Vatican’s role in slavery. But what does it mean for Black Catholics?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Inquirer.com</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 14:21:59</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#1a42ccce17ae</link></item><item><title>VIDEO: Dutch Police toss pregnant woman to ground during husband's arrest, incident sparks outrage o...</title><description>VIDEO: Dutch Police toss pregnant woman to ground during husband's arrest, incident sparks outrage online&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WIONWhy Was A Pregnant Palestinian Woman Thrown to the Floor by Dutch Police?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Out Loud with AhmedOutrage as video shows Dutch police officer assaulting pregnant woman&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Peoples Gazette NigeriaNetherlands: New video of police using force at asylum center&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;InfoMigrantsBaghaei deplores Dutch police attack on Palestinian&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Mehr News Agency</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 09:18:00</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2ca160a66121</link></item><item><title>Pirate-themed party boat sinks, forcing passengers, including children, to jump into sea - WKRC</title><description>Pirate-themed party boat sinks, forcing passengers, including children, to jump into sea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;WKRC148 People, Including 20 Children, Forced to Jump into Sea as Pirate-Themed Party Boat Sinks&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;People.comNearly 150 passengers forced to jump into sea as pirate tour boat sinks in Turkey&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;KUSA.comPassengers take desperate measures to flee as party boat off ‘Paradise Island’ capsizes&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New York Post"Pirate Party" Boat Carrying 148 Tourists Sinks In Turkey, Passengers Jump Into Sea&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;NDTV</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 06:20:37</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#0459ede5f133</link></item><item><title>Race to build Canada’s next submarine fleet enters its final stretch - Global News</title><description>Race to build Canada’s next submarine fleet enters its final stretch&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Global NewsSouth Korean Attack Boat Arrives in Canada Ahead of Submarine Program Decision&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;USNI NewsSponsored Content: The Fleet That Builds a Nation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;PoliticoSouth Korea Sweetens Canada Sub Bid With Rocket Launch Promises as Ottawa Takes Its Time to Decide&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Defense ExpressPresidential Chief of Staff Kang Departs for Canada to Support Submarine Bid&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;조선일보</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 20:33:55</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#614624f567d1</link></item><item><title>Can Britain’s Greens Become a Working-Class Party? - Jacobin</title><description>Can Britain’s Greens Become a Working-Class Party?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Jacobin</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 19:26:14</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#564c916e64de</link></item><item><title>How Many Pantsir Systems Has russia Placed on Moscow Rooftops to Protect Kremlin From Ukrainian Dron...</title><description>How Many Pantsir Systems Has russia Placed on Moscow Rooftops to Protect Kremlin From Ukrainian Drones&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Defense Express‘There’s going to be more and more incidents like the drone attack’ – Nina Khrushcheva&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Channel 4Video appears to show rooftop air defenses being installed on Moscow business tower wedged between GRU base and residential buildings&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;MeduzaRussia Deploys New Missile Systems on Civilian High-Rises to Stop Drone Invasions&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Kyiv PostRussian Mi-26 Airlifts Pantsir AD System onto Moscow Rooftops to Counter Ukrainian Drone Onslaught&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;EurAsian Times</description><pubDate>2026-05-31 07:35:49</pubDate><link>https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shawnkasaei/news-reader-meli/refs/heads/main/Feeds/view/index.html#2675a528f55b</link></item></channel></RSS>